SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Masters in Computer Science JavaScript, Java, Ruby, SQL

Elected to public office at the age of 26.

6 Years of Experience in Venture Capital A software engineer with a Masters in Computer Science and previous venture capital experience. A background contributing to large software development teams and completing successful independent software projects. Enterprise, startup and public sector experience across a number of industries provides a unique perspective and skill set.

Data analysis, business development and operations experience allows for contribution to a range of teams, and often contributes a unique software development perspective. Additional skills and experience in: JavaScript, Ruby, Java, C#. Angular, Backbone, jQuery. Mocha, Chai, Jasmine, jUnit, Selenium, Moq. Git, SQL. HTML, CSS, SASS LESS. Node, NPM, Puppet, Grunt, Jenkins. Agile, Kanban Six Sigma, Lean.

EXPERIENCE

GOOGLE, New York City, NY

2015 - Present

Software Engineer (Javascript, Angular, CSS, architecture planning for the development of a new complex product)

THE NEW YORK TIMES, New York City, NY

2014 - 2015

Software Engineer (Javascript, Backbone, SASS, Mocha, Chai, Sinon, serving tens of millions of users per day)

■ Publisher's Award Winner For contributions to the team developing The New York Times Collections

ZOCDOC, New York City, NY

2013 - 2014

Software Engineer (JavaScript, Backbone, JQuery, CSS, LESS, SQL, Moq, development in a large code base)

PEARL STREET VENTURE FUNDS, Indianapolis, IN

2006 – 2011

Analyst (Performed analysis and research to identify, select, and execute early stage venture investments)

- YourEncore Secured a high-profile partnership. Managed a large operating and forecast financial model
- BioVigilant Systems Performed due diligence that led a \$2.1 million investment, through to a \$17 million exit.
- Colucid Pharmaceuticals Built financial models to support decisions around a \$400 million buyout offer.

KIPTRONIC, San Francisco, CA

2005 - 2006

Director of Business Development (early stage venture-backed advertising technology startup)

TEXTBOOK ALTERNATIVE, Indianapolis, IN

2004 - 2005

Business Development Associate (co-founded college textbook operation that is still profitable)

PUBLIC SERVICE

NEW YORK CITY DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION, New York City, NY

2013 – Present

Computer Science Teacher

Volunteer through the TEALS program to teach a AP Compuer Science class (Java) at a NYC public high school.

CITY COUNCIL, West Lafayette, IN

2008 - 2010

City Councilor

Elected with six other councilors to oversee 185 city employees and a \$26 million operating budget on behalf of 29,000 constituents. Authored and passed three ordinances into law. Worked with diverse constituent groups.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF CHICAGO, Chicago, IL **Masters, Computer Science** (3.8 GPA)

2012 - 2013

PURDUE UNIVERSITY, West Lafayette, IN

1999 - 2004

Bachelor of Science, Industrial Technology (founded Purdue's student-run radio station AM1610)

MISCELLANEOUS

First programmed on an Apple IIe. Wrote first business plan at age 14. Always searching for fresh news.